webfluential.com 2018-06-30

# Webfluential | Privacy

Webfluential collects some Personal Data from its Users. Webfluential respects the privacy of its users and is committed to processing and protecting your Personal Information lawfully.

Data Controller and Owner

Webfluential Global Limited, +27 82 875 1127 , support@webfluential.com

## Types of Data collected

In order to use the Services, you will be required to register an account with Webfluential. During this registration process, you will be asked to provide Webfluential with Personal Information. Among the types of Personal Data that Webfluential collects, by itself or through third parties, there are:

  * First Name & Last Name
  * Phone number
  * Email
  * Address, State, Province, ZIP/Postal code, City
  * Banking details
  * Password
  * Cookie and Usage Data.

Other Personal Data collected may be described in other sections of this privacy policy or by dedicated explanation text contextually with the Data collection.

The Personal Data may be freely provided by the User, or collected automatically when using Webfluential.

Any use of Cookies – or of other tracking tools – by Webfluential or by the owners of third party services used by Webfluential, unless stated otherwise, serves to identify Users and remember their preferences, for the sole purpose of providing the service required by the User.

Failure to provide certain Personal Data may make it impossible for Webfluential to provide its services.

Users are responsible for any Personal Data of third parties obtained, published or shared through Webfluential and confirm that they have the third party’s consent to provide the Data to the Owner.

## Mode and place of processing the Data

### Methods of processing

The Data Controller processes the Data of Users in a proper manner and shall take appropriate security measures to prevent unauthorized access, disclosure, modification, or unauthorized destruction of the Data. The Data processing is carried out using computers and/or IT enabled tools, following organizational procedures and modes strictly related to the purposes indicated. In addition to the Data Controller, in some cases, the Data may be accessible to certain types of persons in charge, involved with the operation of the site (administration, sales, marketing, legal, system administration) or external parties (such as third party technical service providers, mail carriers, hosting providers, IT companies, communications agencies) appointed, if necessary, as Data Processors by the Owner. The updated list of these parties may be requested from the Data Controller at any time.

### Place

The Data is processed at the Data Controller’s operating offices and in any other places where the parties involved with the processing are located. For further information, please contact the Data Controller.

### Retention time

The Data is kept for the time necessary to provide the service requested by the User, or stated by the purposes outlined in this document, and the User can always request that the Data Controller suspend or remove the data.

## The use of the collected Data

The Data concerning the User is collected to allow the Owner to provide its services, as well as for the following purposes: Registration and authentication, Remarketing and Behavioral Targeting, Handling payments, Analytics, User database management, Contacting the User, Managing email addresses and sending messages, Advertising, Infrastructure monitoring, Social features, Hosting and backend as a service and Access to third party services’ accounts.

The Personal Data used for each purpose is outlined in the specific sections of this document.

## Detailed information on the processing of Personal Data

Personal Data is collected for the following purposes and using the following services:

### Access to third party services’ accounts

These services allow Webfluential to access Data from your account on a third party service and perform actions with it.

These services are not activated automatically, but require explicit authorization by the User.

#### Access to the Stripe account (Stripe Inc)

This service allows Webfluential to connect with the User’s account on the Stripe network, provided by Stripe, Inc.

Personal Data collected: Various types of Data as specified in the privacy policy of the service.

Place of processing: USA – [Privacy Policy](https://www.google.com/url?q=https://stripe.com/us/privacy&sa=D&ust=1516311272639000&usg=AFQjCNGlgDwDLU6loG3bQYsaBPr3adO3_w)

#### Access to Google account services

When you use Google services, you trust Google with your information. This [Privacy Policy](https://www.google.com/url?q=https://www.google.com/policies/privacy/&sa=D&ust=1516311272640000&usg=AFQjCNGVBSUmHX_NoN-O451FrjExHnQVbw) is meant to help you understand what data is collected, why it is collected, and what Google does with it. You can find controls to manage your information and protect your privacy and security at [My Account](https://www.google.com/url?q=https://myaccount.google.com/?hl%3Den&sa=D&ust=1516311272641000&usg=AFQjCNFng2kd23VUPK-pPULL-l4feIeO5Q) on Google.

### Advertising

These services allow User Data to be utilized for advertising communication purposes displayed in the form of banners and other advertisements on Webfluential, possibly based on User interests.

This does not mean that all Personal Data are used for this purpose. Information and conditions of use are shown below.

Some of the services listed below may use Cookies to identify Users or they may use the behavioral retargeting technique, i.e. displaying ads tailored to the User’s interests and behavior, including those detected outside Webfluential. For more information, please check the privacy policies of the relevant services.

#### Google AdSense (Google)

Google AdSense is an advertising service provided by Google Inc. This service uses the “Doubleclick” Cookie, which tracks use of Webfluential and User behavior concerning ads, products and services offered.

Users may decide to disable all the Doubleclick Cookies by clicking on:google.com/settings/ads/onweb/optout?hl=en.

Personal Data collected: Cookie and Usage Data.

Place of processing: USA – [Privacy Policy](https://www.google.com/url?q=http://google.com/privacy/ads/&sa=D&ust=1516311272644000&usg=AFQjCNFxMRDu8z-vAMtnfJjbi8INvt-udg)

### Analytics

The services contained in this section enable the Owner to monitor and analyze web traffic and can be used to keep track of User behavior.

#### Google Analytics (Google)

Google Analytics is a web analysis service provided by Google Inc. (“Google”). Google utilizes the Data collected to track and examine the use of Webfluential, to prepare reports on its activities and share them with other Google services.

Google may use the Data collected to contextualize and personalize the ads of its own advertising network.

Personal Data collected: Cookie and Usage Data.

Place of processing: USA – [Privacy Policy](https://www.google.com/url?q=http://www.google.com/intl/en/policies/privacy/&sa=D&ust=1516311272646000&usg=AFQjCNGEKVaAmgglqBTSiHHIx5PqdnUGvw) – [Opt Out](https://www.google.com/url?q=http://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout?hl%3Den&sa=D&ust=1516311272646000&usg=AFQjCNHsjLVF2u0wZd242XXzu7rUxts6sA)

### Contacting the User

#### Mailing List or Newsletter (Webfluential)

By registering on the mailing list or for the newsletter, the User’s email address will be added to the contact list of those who may receive email messages containing information of commercial or promotional nature concerning Webfluential. Your email address might also be added to this list as a result of signing up to Webfluential or after making a purchase.

Personal Data collected: Name, email, telephone number, company name, location

#### Contact form (Webfluential)

By filling in the contact form with their Data, the User authorizes Webfluential to use these details to reply to requests for information, quotes or any other kind of request as indicated by the form’s header.

Personal Data collected: Name, email, telephone number, company name, location

### Handling payments

Payment processing services enable Webfluential to process payments by credit card, bank transfer or other means. To ensure greater security, Webfluential shares only the information necessary to execute the transaction with the financial intermediaries handling the transaction.

#### Stripe (Stripe Inc)

Stripe is a payment service provided by Stripe Inc.

Personal Data collected: Various types of Data as specified in the privacy policy of the service.

Place of processing: USA – [Privacy Policy](https://www.google.com/url?q=https://stripe.com/terms/US&sa=D&ust=1516311272649000&usg=AFQjCNF00sPdHHl2-fmdUfZEpIrHDVHVwg)

#### PayPal (PayPal Inc.)

PayPal is a payment service provided by PayPal Inc., which allows users to make online payments using their Paypal credentials.

Personal Data collected: Various types of Data as specified in the privacy policy of the service.

### Hosting and backend as a service

These services have the purpose of hosting data and files that enable Webfluential to run and be distributed as well as to provide a ready-made infrastructure to run specific features or parts of Webfluential. Some of these services work through geographically distributed servers, making it difficult to determine the actual location where the Personal Data are stored.

#### DigitalOcean (DigitalOcean Inc.)

DigitalOcean is a hosting service provided by DigitalOcean Inc.

Personal Data collected: Various types of Data as specified in the privacy policy of the service.

Place of processing: UK – [Privacy Policy](https://www.google.com/url?q=https://www.digitalocean.com/legal/privacy/&sa=D&ust=1516311272652000&usg=AFQjCNEExeCk9xsdAaVoU7zvnDAJTYq0ng)

#### Hetzner (Hetzner Pty Ltd)

Hetzner is a hosting service provided by Hetzner Pty Ltd.

Personal Data collected: Various types of Data as specified in the privacy policy of the service.

Place of processing: South Africa – [Privacy Policy](https://www.google.com/url?q=https://hetzner.co.za/legal/privacy-policy/&sa=D&ust=1516311272654000&usg=AFQjCNF3fl4WMP7Xkx3jtRSax45uKZyDbA)

Place of processing: Germany – [Privacy Policy](https://www.google.com/url?q=https://www.hetzner.com/rechtliches/datenschutz)

### Managing email addresses and sending messages

These services make it possible to manage a database of email contacts to communicate with the User via email.

The services are used to collect data concerning the date and time when the mail is viewed by the User, as well as when the User interacts with incoming mail, such as by clicking on links included in the email.

#### Mailchimp (Mailchimp)

Mailchimp is an email address management and message sending service provided by Mailchimp Inc.

Personal Data collected: Email.

Place of processing: USA – [Privacy Policy](https://www.google.com/url?q=http://mailchimp.com/legal/privacy/&sa=D&ust=1516311272656000&usg=AFQjCNF9XHyh2CL9cGg0Ye_RLL9p5Msd9Q)

### Registration and authentication

By registering or authenticating, Users allow Webfluential to identify them and give them access to dedicated services.

Depending on what is described below, third parties may provide registration and authentication services.

In this case, Webfluential will be able to access some Data, stored by these third party services, for registration or identification purposes.

#### Direct registration (Webfluential)

The User registers by filling out the registration form and providing the Personal Data directly to Webfluential.

Personal Data collected: Address, City, Email, First Name, Last Name, Password, Phone number, Province, State and ZIP/Postal code.

#### Twitter OAuth (Twitter)

Twitter Oauth is a registration and authentication service provided by Twitter Inc. and is connected to the Twitter social network.

Personal Data collected: Various types of Data as specified in the privacy policy of the service.

Place of processing: USA – [Privacy Policy](https://www.google.com/url?q=https://developer.twitter.com/en/developer-terms/policy&sa=D&ust=1516311272658000&usg=AFQjCNFjb0urvKMg3sGwsbCbIJ2eJkdqdQ)

#### Google OAuth (Google)

Google OAuth is a registration and authentication service provided by Google Inc. and is connected to the Google network.

Personal Data collected: Various types of Data as specified in the privacy policy of the service.

Place of processing: USA – [Privacy Policy](https://www.google.com/url?q=https://www.google.com/policies/privacy/&sa=D&ust=1516311272659000&usg=AFQjCNHO6LDjT8VSwzXedEWNgqxwEQ2TMg)

### Remarketing and Behavioral Targeting

These services allow Webfluential and its partners to inform, optimize and serve advertising based on past use of Webfluential by the User.

This activity is performed by tracking Usage Data and by using Cookies, information that is transferred to the partners that manage the remarketing and behavioral targeting activity.

#### Twitter Remarketing (Twitter)

Twitter Remarketing is a Remarketing and Behavioral Targeting service provided by Twitter, Inc. that connects the activity of Webfluential with the Twitter advertising network.

Personal Data collected: Cookie and Usage Data.

Place of processing: USA – [Privacy Policy](https://www.google.com/url?q=https://developer.twitter.com/en/developer-terms/policy&sa=D&ust=1516311272661000&usg=AFQjCNHRHPr0dF2fJ9eGkMNRd7EpzgQ6vw) – [Opt Out](https://www.google.com/url?q=https://support.twitter.com/articles/20170405&sa=D&ust=1516311272662000&usg=AFQjCNH8djDlLMr-Wu-IujIH70DlSNbndQ)

#### Facebook Remarketing (Facebook)

Facebook Remarketing is a Remarketing and Behavioral Targeting service provided by Facebook Inc. that connects the activity of Webfluential with the Facebook advertising network.

Personal Data collected: Cookie and Usage Data.

Place of processing: USA – [Privacy Policy](https://www.google.com/url?q=https://www.facebook.com/about/privacy/&sa=D&ust=1516311272663000&usg=AFQjCNHfg-uQqIvDOkho_NL1Wn5hOnYxCg)

### Social features

#### Inviting and suggesting friends (Webfluential)

Webfluential may use the Personal Data provided to allow Users to invite their friends – for example through the address book, if access has been provided – and to suggest friends or connections inside it.

Personal Data collected: Various types of Data as specified in the privacy policy of the service.

### Personality analysis

#### IBM Watson (IBM)

Webfluential may use publicly accessible data, authenticated social content and/or explicit User input data to process and generate a Personality profile for the purpose of optimised networking. 

Place of processing: USA – [Privacy Policy](https://www.google.com/url?q=https://www.ibm.com/watson/data-privacy/)

### User database management

These services build user profiles by starting from an email address, a personal name, or other information that the User provides to Webfluential. This Personal Data is matched with publicly available information about the User (such as social networks’ profiles) and used to build private profiles that the Owner can display and use for improving Webfluential.

#### Intercom (Intercom Inc.)

Intercom is a User database management service provided by Intercom Inc.

Personal Data collected: Email and Various types of Data as specified in the privacy policy of the service.

Place of processing: USA – [Privacy Policy](https://www.google.com/url?q=http://docs.intercom.io/privacy.html&sa=D&ust=1516311272665000&usg=AFQjCNEYA9Y2WSH6QyQiTTgnxJgGvjxEyg)

## Further information about Personal Data

### The use of the Data processed by the Service

All Data processed via the analysis conducted by Webfluential are used by Webfluential only for the purpose of providing the service to the Users. Such Data will not be transferred or sold by Webfluential to any third party, nor will it be used by the Owner for any purpose connected to Webfluential’s own business. The Owner reserves the right to aggregate the Data imported on the application by the different Webfluential Users, for the purpose of creating anonymized aggregated metrics.

### Selling goods and services online

The Personal Data collected are used to provide the User with services, including payment and possible delivery.

The Personal Data collected to complete the payment may include the credit card, the bank account used for the transfer, or any other means of payment envisaged. The kind of Data collected by Webfluential depends on the payment system used.

## Additional information about data collection and processing

### Legal action

The User’s Personal Data may be used for legal purposes by the Data Controller, in Court or in the stages leading to possible legal action arising from improper use of Webfluential or the related services.

The User declares to be aware that the Data Controller may be required to reveal personal data upon request of public authorities.

### Additional information about user’s personal data

In addition to the information contained in this privacy policy, Webfluential may provide the User with additional and contextual information concerning particular services or the collection and processing of Personal Data upon request.

### Safety and Security

#### Webfluential uses all reasonable technical and organisational measures to secure the integrity of the Personal Information under its control and prevent the loss of, damage to or unauthorised destruction of your Personal Information and unlawful access to or Processing of your Personal Information. When you enter sensitive information (such as a credit card number or banking details) on our registration forms, we encrypt that information using secure socket layer technology (SSL).

### System logs and maintenance

For operation and maintenance purposes, Webfluential and any third party services may collect files that record interaction with Webfluential (System Logs) or use for this purpose other Personal Data (such as IP Address).

### Information not contained in this policy

More details concerning the collection or processing of Personal Data may be requested from the Data Controller at any time. Please see the contact information at the beginning of this document.

### The rights of users

Users have the right, at any time, to know whether their Personal Data has been stored and can consult the Data Controller to learn about their contents and origin, to verify their accuracy or to ask for them to be supplemented, cancelled, updated or corrected, or for their transformation into anonymous format or to block any data held in violation of the law, as well as to oppose their treatment for any and all legitimate reasons. 

Requests should be sent to the Data Controller at the contact information set out above. Webfluential does not support “Do Not Track” requests. To determine whether any of the third party services it uses honor the “Do Not Track” requests, please read their privacy policies.

### Additional Rights for EEA users or similar international areas

If You live in the European Economic Area, or a similar international area, You may have additional privacy rights available to You under applicable laws. We will process Your requests in accordance with applicable data protection laws. If You would like to exercise any of the below rights, please contact support@webfluential.com so that We may consider Your request in accordance with applicable law: 

  * **Right of Access** \- the right to be informed of and request access to the personal data we process about you;
  * **Right to Rectification** \- the right to request that we amend or update your personal data where it is inaccurate or incomplete;
  * **Right to Erasure** \- the right to request that we delete your personal data;
  * **Right to Restrict** \- the right to request that we temporarily or permanently stop processing all or some of your personal data;
  * **Right to Object** \- 
    * the right, at any time, to object to us processing your personal data on grounds relating to your particular situation;
    * the right to object to your personal data being processed for direct marketing purposes;
  * **Right to Data Portability** \- the right to request a copy of your personal data in electronic format and the right to transmit that personal data for use in another party’s service; and
  * **Right not to be subject to Automated Decision-making** \- the right to not be subject to a decision based solely on automated decision making, including profiling, where the decision would have a legal effect on you or produce a similarly significant effect.

### How long We retain Your information

We will retain personal information We collect from You for the period allowable by law and where We have a justifiable business need to do so, unless a longer period is required or permitted by law. You can request deletion of Your Personal Data at any time and We will consider Your request in accordance with applicable law.

### Changes to this privacy policy

We may occasionally make changes to this Policy.

When we make material changes to this Policy, we’ll provide you with prominent notice as appropriate under the circumstances, e.g., by displaying a prominent notice within the Webfluential Service or by sending you an email. We may notify you in advance.

Please, therefore, make sure you read any such notice carefully. If a User objects to any of the changes to the Policy, the User must cease using Webfluential and can request that the Data Controller removes the Personal Data. Unless stated otherwise, the then-current privacy policy applies to all Personal Data the Data Controller has about Users. 

### Information about this privacy policy

The Data Controller is responsible for this privacy policy, prepared starting from the modules provided by Iubenda and hosted on Iubenda’s servers.

## Definitions and legal references

### Personal data (or data)

Any information regarding a natural person, a legal person, an institution or an association, which is, or can be, identified, even indirectly, by reference to any other information, including a personal identification number.

### Usage data

Information collected automatically from Webfluential (or third party services employed in Webfluential ), which can include: the IP addresses or domain names of the computers utilized by the Users who use Webfluential, the URI addresses (Uniform Resource Identifier), the time of the request, the method utilized to submit the request to the server, the size of the file received in response, the numerical code indicating the status of the server’s answer (successful outcome, error, etc.), the country of origin, the features of the browser and the operating system utilized by the User, the various time details per visit (e.g., the time spent on each page within the Application) and the details about the path followed within the Application with special reference to the sequence of pages visited, and other parameters about the device operating system and/or the User’s IT environment.

### User

The individual using Webfluential, which must coincide with or be authorized by the Data Subject, to whom the Personal Data refer.

### Data subject

The legal or natural person to whom the Personal Data refers.

### Data processor (or Data supervisor)

The natural person, legal person, public administration or any other body, association or organization authorized by the Data Controller to process the Personal Data in compliance with this privacy policy.

### Data controller (or owner)

The natural person, legal person, public administration or any other body, association or organization with the right, also jointly with another Data Controller, to make decisions regarding the purposes, and the methods of processing of Personal Data and the means used, including the security measures concerning the operation and use of Webfluential. The Data Controller, unless otherwise specified, is the Owner of Webfluential.

### Webfluential

The hardware or software tool by which the Personal Data of the User is collected.

### Cookies

Small piece of data stored in the User’s device.

## Legal information

Notice to European Users: this privacy statement has been prepared in fulfillment of the obligations under Art. 10 of EC Directive n. 95/46/EC, and under the provisions of Directive 2002/58/EC, as revised by Directive 2009/136/EC, on the subject of Cookies.

This privacy policy relates solely to Webfluential.
